Rohan Gonjari

Boston, MA | (774) 301-6307 | rohan.gonjari@outlook.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a Data Analytics expert with expertise in data science and optimizing machine learning models. As a Data Analyst, I reduced expenses for 120+ businesses using regression models and Tableau. I have strong technical skills in Python, MATLAB, R, SQL, and AWS, and I've contributed to a publication on Multimodal Auditory BCI Classification through Graph Neural Networks.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer/Research Assistant | UMass Dartmouth | North Dartmouth, MA

Aug 2022 – Aug 2023

- Data Processing for imbalanced classification of Multi-View data through feature selection, feature elimination, & data sampling.
- Generated & manipulated graph data for Graph CNNs & popular ML models to implement supervised machine learning.
- Modelled neural networks, manipulating layers & hyperparameters to improve performance for GCNs.
- Performed dimensionality reduction (t-SNE) to help visualize graph nodes and edges using Seaborn.

Data Analyst | Destek Infosolutions | India

Aug 2020 - July 2023

- Collaborated with 120+ businesses through the end-to-end completion of e-commerce platforms with a 95% success rate.
- Initiated a data sourcing project, establishing a robust data pipeline for sourcing new data & cleansing old data, then further process data for feature elimination & selection using NumPy & Panda's libraries.
- Used regression models for targeted customer segmentation, resulting in a substantial 18% sales boost.
- Developed different **Tableau** dashboards to have more visibility of Desteks sales portfolio for different products.

- EDUCATION

University of Massachusetts Dartmouth | North Dartmouth, MA

Sept 2021 -Aug 2023

- Masters of Science in Data Science
- Coursework: High-Performance Scientific Computing, Advanced Data Mining, Advanced Machine Learning, Data Visualization, Data Design & Systems, Business Analytics, Graph Neural Networks

National Institute of Technology Karnataka (NITK), Surathkal | India

July 2016 – June 2020

- Bachelor of Technology in Electronics & Communications Engineering
- Coursework: Numerical Analysis, Discrete Mathematical Structures, Data Structures & Algorithms, Statistical Analysis

PROJECTS

Multimodality-Enhanced Graph Generation & Multimodality-Driven GCN | Master's Thesis

Aug 2022 – Aug 2023

- Proposed adaptable novel methodologies MEGG & MDGCN to work with Multi-View data across various industries.
- Novel methods showcased an improvement in performance by 16.25% & 21.65% in two distinct studies.
- Modified models to achieve high immunity & robustness to noisy & corrupted data when injected with Gaussian Noise.

Hospital Management System (HMS)

Sept 2022 - Dec 2022

- Designed a database to implement an HMS & ensure functional integrity. Then generated tables & attributes using MySQL.
- Built a user interface to help users navigate through the database using Python & MySQL connector.

Evaluating Medical Condition of Patients

Feb 2022 - April 2022

- Performed EDA to determine significant features based on correlation & multiple Regression models.
- Built Regression model with Cross-Validation & Recursive Feature Elimination with significant & engineered features.
- Developed Random Forest & Gradient Boosted Decision Tree models & determined the best model based on RMSE.

Visualizing Olympics Performance

Jan 2022 – April 2022

- Sourced Olympics data between 1960 2016 to build dynamic & interactive visualizations using D3 in JavaScript.
- Built a web framework using HTML & CSS with added navigation to other visualizations built by team members.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Technologies: Python | MATLAB | R-Programming | SQL | MySQL | SAS | Java | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Tableau
- Libraries: PyTorch | PyG | SciKit-Learn | TensorFlow | Matplotlib | Pandas | Numpy | XGBoost | Seaborn
- AWS: SageMaker | S3 | Snowflake